A Guide to the Joseph Kieffer Ruebush, Frederick County Papers, 1788-1888
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Joseph Kieffer Ruebush, Frederick County Papers, 1788-1888
Library of Virginia
23718
51 leaves and 61 pages.
Joseph Kieffer Ruebush
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Purchased from Joseph Kieffer Ruebush, Harrisonburg, Virginia, on 7 September 1951.
Biographical/Historical Information
Joseph Kieffer Ruebush was born 26 October 1878 in Dayton, Rockingham County, Virginia. He attended Shenandoah College and Ohio State University's school of journalism. Ruebush operated the Ruebush-Kieffer press in Rockingham County for several years. As a historian, he wrote on Rockingham County and on the Shenandoah Valley. Ruebush served as one of the first trustees of the Rockingham County Public Library, on the Civil War Centennial Commission, and the Shenandoah Valley Civil War Roundtable. He was a founder of the Rockingham Historical Society. He married Nancy Byrd Rhodes (d. 1952). Ruebush died 25 July 1963 in Harrisonburg, Virginia.
Scope and Content Information
Frederick County, Virginia, papers, 1788-1888, collected by Joseph K. Ruebush (1878-1963) of Harrisonburg, Virginia, consisting of: abstracts, announcements, bonds, certificates, certificates of ordination, correspondence, decrees, deeds, judicial records, land grants, plats, receipts, reports, surveys, warrants, and wills mainly of the Evard and Clevenger families of Frederick County and Winchester, Virginia.
Subjects covered by the collection are: freedmen, the Freedmen's Bureau, and Reconstruction in Alabama; the Church of Christ at Galilee and the clergy in Frederick County, Virginia; decedents' estates, land titles, local taxation, and slaves in Frederick County; Frederick County overseers of the poor and illegitimate children; and the history of Frederick County in the eighteenth and nineteenth centuries. Also contains papers relating to the history of the following families: Browning, Clevenger, Evard, Gruber, McClay, Peters, Stephens, and Wilson.
Arrangement
Arranged chronologically with licenses and receipts located at the end.
Contents List
- Grant. 19 acres in Frederick County to George Holt, Sr., by Beverly Randolph, Governor of Virginia, 8 December 1788, A-1; 1 p., printed form.
- Letter. John Hopkins, Richmond, to John Wickham, 5 February [17]99, A-2; 1 p.
- Decree. Norborne B. Beall vs. Absalom Bainbridge, Jefferson Circuit Court, July term, 1811, A-3; 2 p., copy.
- Will. Henry Stephens, Frederick County, dated 10 March 1826, A-4; 3 p., copy.
- Deed. Jacob R. Nickling and wife Clarissa, to Joseph Hackney, both parties of Frederick County, 116 acres in Frederick County, dated 3 November 1826 and recorded Frederick County, 3 November 1826, A-5; 4 p.
- Letter. Charlotte [___], Philadelphia, to George F. Schaeffer, New York, 21 January 1835, A-6; 2 p.
- Report. Overseers of the Poor, [Frederick County?], regarding Maria Mitchell, 3 June 1835, A-7; 1 p.
- Warrant. Officials of Frederick County to apprehend Robert Smith, 12 November 1839, A-8; 1 p.
- Bond. Sarah Orndorff and Levi Orndorff, Frederick County, to Overseers of the Poor, Frederick County, dated 21 November 1839, A-9; 1 p.
- Deed. Jacob R. Nicklin to John Pugh and Lewis George, 123 1/4 acreas in Frederick County, dated 28(?) January 1852, A-10; 1 p.
- Letter. A. Lafore, Philadelphia, to Charles Eugene Evard, Winchester, 11 March 1852, A-11; 1 p.
- Certificate. G. B. Graves, Commissioner of Winchester, regarding Charles E. Evard, 12 February 1853, A-12; 1 p.
- Letter. [___], Winchester, to [___], 26 November 1853, A-13; 1 p.
- Deed. Jesse Wright and wife, Lydia, to John Pugh and Lewis George, 123 1/4 acres in Frederick County, dated 10 March 1853, Corporation of Winchester, A-14; 4 p.
- Deed. John Pugh of Warren County, and Lewis George and wife, Rebecca, of Frederick County, to Alfred Clevenger, 123 1/4 acres in Frederick County, dated 25 October 1854 and recorded Frederick County, 16 April 1855, A-15; 4 p.
- Will. Mary B. Wilson, Frederick County, dated 18 August 1855, A-16; 4 p., copy.
- Letter. [___] Evard, Winchester, to [___], 9 January 1856, A-17; 1 p.
- Will. Felix Roberts, Frederick County, dated 5 February 1859 and recorded 28 February 1859, A-18; 4 p., copy.
- Letter. [___] Bourquin, Chaux de fonds, [France], to Felix Roberts, Winchester, Virginia, 23 April 1853, A-19; 1 p.
- Deed. Henry M. Brent, executor of Felix Roberts, deceased, to James T. Clevenger, 700 acres in Frederick County, dated 15 August 1859, A-20; 4 p.
- Letter. Constance G. Racine(?), Chaux de fonds, [France], to cousin, Constance [Evard], Winchester, 15 December 1859, A-21; 2 p.
- Letter. Constance G. Racine(?), Chaux de fonds, [France], to cousin, Constance Evard, Winchester, 13(?) June 1860, A-22; 4 p.
- Letter. Rosine Wholey, Staunton, to [___], 6 Novembr 1860, A-23; 2 p.
- Letter. [___], Winchester, to aunt and uncle, [___], 17 April 1861, A-24; 2 p., unsigned.
- Letter. [___] to Mrs. Constance I(?). Clevenger, Frederick County, [1862?], A-25; 1 p.
- Letter. T(?). Wall, Walton, to Mrs. Constance I. Clevenger, [Frederick County], 6 March [18]63, A-26; 2 p.
- Letter. H. M. Brent, Winchester, to James T. Clevenger, Frederick County, 7 April 1863, A-27; 1 p.
- Letter. Virginia [___], Montgomery, Alabama, to [___], 14 January [18]66, A-28; 4 p.
- Plats. 64 acres and 11 acres near Winchester belonging to James Clevenger, by E. S. Baker, surveyor, 25 January 1867, A-29; 2 p.
- Letter. Virginia B. [___], Montgomery, Alabama, to sister, [___], 29 January [18]67, A-30; 4 p.
- Letter. Virginia [___], Salem, Massachusetts, to sister, [___], 12 January [18]68, A-31; 4 p.
- Letter. Virginia Browning, Vineland, New Jersey, to sister, [___], 15 October [18]68, A-32; 1 p.
- Plat. 51 acres belonging to James T. Clavenger, by D. W. Branson(?), surveyor, 7 November 1870, A-33; 1 p.
- Division. Land of Felix Roberts, Frederick County, by John Moling, county surveyor, 4 March 1874, A-34; 8 p.
- Certificate. James T. Clevenger, ordained as minister by the Church of Christ at Galilee, 27 November 1874, A-35; 1 p.
- Bond. Alfred Clevenger and James T. Clevenger to John Stephenson, 15 December 1875, A-36; 4 p.
- Certificate. House and lot belonging to John P. Bash sold at auction to O. D. Finfrock, Winchester, by J. L. Redmon(?), auctioneer, 12 May 1888, A-37; 1 p.
- Letter. J. Peyton Clark to [___] Evard, n.d., A-38; 1 p.
- Plat. 565 acres known as "Hackwood," [Frederick County], made for F. Roberts, n.d., A-39; 1 p.
- Licenses and receipts dated 1845-1848, 1851-1854, 1856, 1873, and undated, A-40; 21 items, printed forms and manuscripts.